<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Codes on benfb</title>
    <link>https://benbailey.me/code/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Codes on benfb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 13:46:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://benbailey.me/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>cumulus</title>
      <link>https://benbailey.me/cumulus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 13:46:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benbailey.me/cumulus/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus is a command-line tool for injecting CoreOS cloud-configs into AWS Cloud Formation templates go get github.com/benfb/cumulus go install github.com/benfb/cumulus  Why? CoreOS is a great operating system for running Docker contianers, and it can be configured easily using Cloud-Config. However, if you want to use Amazon&amp;rsquo;s CloudFormation to create easily replicable CoreOS stacks, you need to inject the Cloud-Config into the CloudFormation template. Cumulus makes it easy to do so without having to manually escape quotes, add newlines, and copy and paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>elixush</title>
      <link>https://benbailey.me/elixush/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 13:46:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benbailey.me/elixush/</guid>
      <description>Elixush is an Elixir-based interpreter for the Push genetic programming language. Reasoning Elixir runs every function in its own process on the virtual machine. The Elixir virtual machine has a much faster startup time than the JVM. The well-established OTP architecture in place here makes concurrency and parallelism much easier to implement than in Clojush. By focusing only on the interpreter rather than actual genetic programming, Elixush is much easier to maintain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>trackseeker</title>
      <link>https://benbailey.me/trackseeker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:06:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benbailey.me/trackseeker/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Trackseeker. Trackseeker is a tool that uses the Dead Air Removal Service to discover hidden tracks and add them to iTunes.
Often hidden tracks that are ripped from CDs leave the user with a massive file that has the short ending track followed by several minutes of silence and then a short hidden track. Trackseeker removes the silence from these tracks and splits them into two separate files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>go-tumblr</title>
      <link>https://benbailey.me/go-tumblr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 22:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benbailey.me/go-tumblr/</guid>
      <description>A work-in-progress client for the Tumblr API written in Go.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>