<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on benfb</title>
    <link>https://benbailey.me/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on benfb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:06:56 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://benbailey.me/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>trackseeker</title>
      <link>https://benbailey.me/trackseeker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:06:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://benbailey.me/trackseeker/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;welcome-to-trackseeker:61f5fe94dd6908ebdf38e66b9c722bcd&#34;&gt;Welcome to Trackseeker.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trackseeker is a tool that uses the Dead Air Removal Service to discover hidden tracks and add them to iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often hidden tracks that are ripped from CDs leave the user with a massive file that has the short ending track followed by several minutes of silence and then a short hidden track. Trackseeker removes the silence from these tracks and splits them into two separate files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-started:61f5fe94dd6908ebdf38e66b9c722bcd&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ffmpeg is required to be able to use Trackseeker. To learn how to install it on your platform, refer to pydub&amp;rsquo;s documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jiaaro/pydub/#getting-ffmpeg-set-up&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install Trackseeker, just type &lt;code&gt;pip install trackseeker&lt;/code&gt; and pip will install Trackseeker and the two libraries it relies on, dars and pydub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;example:61f5fe94dd6908ebdf38e66b9c722bcd&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to extract the hidden track from Beach House&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Irene.&amp;rdquo; The song is currently 16 minutes long, with about seven minutes of silence between the album closer and the hidden track. I run the command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;trackseeker --artist=&amp;quot;Beach House&amp;quot; --album=&amp;quot;Bloom&amp;quot; --track=&amp;quot;Irene&amp;quot; --num=&amp;quot;10&amp;quot; --fmt=&amp;quot;m4a&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes, two new songs are added to my iTunes library, the shortened version of &amp;ldquo;Irene&amp;rdquo; and the hidden track titled &amp;ldquo;(Hidden Track)&amp;rdquo;. In this case, Trackseeker removed seven minutes of silence and saved 14 MB of space. Not bad!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also run &lt;code&gt;trackseeker&lt;/code&gt; with no arguments to have the program ask for the required information line by line, or view all available arguments with &lt;code&gt;trackseeker -h&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes:61f5fe94dd6908ebdf38e66b9c722bcd&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trackseeker occasionally runs into issues when exporting MP3s. This appears to be a problem with MP3 headers. If anyone knows of a fix for this, please create an issue in the Github project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently Trackseeker only works with iTunes. If you wish to use the silence detection and removal functions, you can use DARS (the Dead Air Removal Service) instead. It isn&amp;rsquo;t as nice to use, but functions well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trackseeker can take a few minutes to run. Get a cup of coffee, make a pros and cons list about getting a cup of coffee, ask someone else if you should get a cup of coffee, grab one anyway, whatever you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deleting the original file is left as an exercise for the reader.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>